# **Umut YILMAZ**

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

**Date of Birth and Place** : 21.09.1990 – Gaziantep/TURKEY

Nationality : Turkish

Driver License : B class (2012)

Address : Tuzla/Istanbul, Turkey

Phone : +90 553 514 48 27

E-mail : umuteyilmaz@gmail.com

Github : github.com/umuteyilmaz

Linkedin : linkedin.com/in/umuteyilmaz



I have technical background as software development and management of system about 9 years. I am enthusiastic administrator in the field of infrastructure and automation solutions. I would be glad if you consider me as a candidate for the employee. I would like to have a conversation if you are interested. Best regards.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

08/20 - Present

#### **Kuveyt Türk Participation Bank**



Unit/Position: Sr. DevOps Engineer

#### Responsibilities:

Developing SDLC and DevOps process

Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher, AWS; RDS, EC2, EKS, CloudWatch, ECR, GCP Redis, Kafka, RabbitMQ, ELK stack, PowerShell, Bash, Ansible, Terraform Jenkins, AzureDevops, Gitlab, SonarQube,Sonatype Nexus, Fortify SCA

RHEL, Windows Server, IIS, Nginx, Apache Tomcat

11/2017 - 08/2020

HAVELSAN - Naval Warfare Management Systems Technology Center



Unit/Position: R&D / DevOps & SysOps Administrator

# Responsibilities:

Server and software release management

Java, Python, C, Bash

Linux (RHEL6,RHEL7,CentOS,Ubuntu), Windows Server, AD, LDAP

AWS, OpenShift, Kubernetes, Docker,

Ansible, MySql, PostgreSql, Prometheus, Grafana

Jenkins, SVN, Git, SonarQube, Jira, TCP/IP, VMware vSphere/ ESXi

4/2016 - 10/2017

TURK TELEKOM

(1 years 8 months)

Unit/Position: Application Development / Software Engineer

# Türk Telekom

Responsibilities:

Avaya IVR Development and System Management

Agile Scrum

Java, Java EE (Webservices, EJB, Servlet ve JSP)

Linux, Apache Tomcat, Red Hat Enterprise Linux MS SQL,

SVN, JIRA, SolarWinds, Avaya VoicePortal, IVR, Contact Center Solutions

4/2015 – 3/2016 (1 years) Intertech Information Technology and Marketing Inc.

intertec

Unit/Position: Application Development / Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities:

Development Banking Software

 $C\#, ASP.NET, MS\ SQL, HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, MS\ Visual\ Studio, Cruise Control. NET$ 

9/2013 - 4/2015

(1 years 7 months)

TUBITAK BILGEM

The Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey Informatics and Information Security

**Research Center** 

Unit/Position: R&D / Researcher - Software Engineer

Responsibilities:

Developed web projects

Java PrimeFaces, JSF, Maven, Jboss, WildFly, Jenkins, Sonar

HTML, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Jira, Eclipse, SVN

10/2011-5/2012

INFORMATICS AND

**Istanbul Technical University** 

(8 months)

**National Center for High Performance Computing** 

*Unit/Position:* R&D / Researcher – System Administrator Responsibilities:

Server Management (Ubuntu, CentOS, Redhat)

Bash, Python and C

Monitoring

Networking, TCP/IP



## **EDUCATION**

09/2017 - 08/2018 International Hoca Ahmet Yesevi Turkish-Kazakh University

MSc Management Information Systems

09/2012 - 06/2017 Anadolu University

**BSc Economics** 

09/2008 – Istanbul Technical University

**BSc Computer Engineering** 

09/2004 - 06/2008 Gaziantep Science High School

Physical Sciences

# **CERTIFICATES**

LFCA: Linux Foundation Certified IT Associate

**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner** 

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Certified Rancher Operator: Level 1

GitLab Certified Associate

# **FELLOWSHIPS & HOBBIES**

Fellowships Gaziantep Science High School Alumni Association

Hobbies Travelling, Music, Photography, Economics, Aircraft and Avitation